Audius Privacy Policy

Last Updated: October 31, 2023

Welcome to Audius! Tiki Labs, Inc. (“Audius,” “we,” “us,” “our”) respects the privacy of our users. This

Privacy Policy describes how we collect, use, and share certain information about you (“you,” “your,”

“user”) in connection with our website located at https://audius.co/, each of the “Audius” branded

desktop and mobile applications, and our blockchain-based streaming platform, https://audius.co/ (the

“Service”). It also explains your rights and choices with respect to such information and the steps you

can take to protect your privacy.

Please read this policy carefully. By visiting or using the Service, clicking “I agree” or any other button

indicating your acceptance of this Privacy Policy, or otherwise providing information to Audius, you are

consenting to the collection, use, and sharing of your information as described in this Privacy Policy.

A note about blockchain: Audius’ streaming service is hosted on blockchain-based networks (POA

Network and Ethereum). Blockchains are immutable, and Audius’ Listeners’ and Creators’ transactions

and certain information about our Listeners and Creators are stored on blockchains (detailed below in

the Section “Information on Blockchain Networks”). Because blockchains are immutable, any Listener

and Creator information that is stored on chain, once created, cannot be changed or removed. You

understand that when you use Audius, any information stored on blockchains will remain there and we

will not be able to remove it.

Audius Users

Audius’ Service is available to different types of users, including Listeners, Creators,

Service/Infrastructure Providers, and Users who visit the Audius website and Service (each individual or

collectively a “user” or “you”). The information that the Service collects from and shares about you may

depend on your user type, and you may interact with the Services in any or all of these user types.

● A Listener is an individual who has registered for the Service to discover and listen to music by

Creators.

● A Creator is an individual who has registered for the Service to share his or her music with other

Listeners and Creators and who may also use the service as a Listener to discover music and

Creators.

● A User is an individual that visits or uses the website, and includes Listeners and Creators.

● A Service/Infrastructure Provider is an individual or company who operates a creator node,

discovery service, content service, or other hosted technology service by running the Audius

open-source code and registering in the network, or who provides arbitration services by

self-registering as an arbitrator. A Service/Infrastructure Provider can also be a Listener, Creator,

User or any combination of the above. Please note, Service/Infrastructure Providers operate

independently of Audius; they are neither employees nor contractors of Audius and are not

otherwise directed or controlled by Audius in any way.

1

Information that We Collect

We and our third-party Vendors collect a variety of information through the Service. We collect

information from you directly when you provide it to us through the Service and when you engage in

certain actions on the Service. We may also automatically collect certain information about you and

your computer, smartphone, or other device when you use, access, or interact with our Service. This

information includes, but is not limited to:

● Account and profile information. In order to create an account for you on the Audius streaming

service as a Listener or Creator, we collect your name, email address, password, and user handle.

You may optionally provide us with a profile photo and your location. We will create a user ID to

be associated with your account.

● Social media information. Listeners and Creators may choose to log in to the Service using a

third-party social media service, such as Twitter or Instagram. If you do so, we collect

information about you from the social media provider, including, for example, your name,

username, email address, and available public profile information. We will ask for your consent

prior to your logging in to the Service using your social media account or connecting your social

media account to the Service.

● Information about your transactions and interactions on the Audius streaming service. We

collect information about you as you interact and transact with our streaming service. For

example, we collect information about the following types of actions taken by Listeners and

Creators: uploading tracks; saving or removing a track from your library; creating, publishing, or

deleting playlists; playlist names; playlist content such as the tracks and the order of the tracks;

albums; actions to repost tracks, albums, or playlists; and following and unfollowing other Users

on Audius. For Creators who upload works to the Service, we collect the tracks uploaded, the

title of the track and the Creator’s user ID, the track length, cover art for the track, information

about the date of creation and release of the track, and any uploaded images.

● Comments on albums, playlists, or tracks. We may offer you the ability to publicly comment on

Listener and Creator albums, playlists, and tracks. When you leave comments, they will be

publicly available and will be associated with your name and user handle.

● Chat messages. Audius may offer chat feature that allows you and other Listeners and Creators

to communicate through the streaming service. Through its vendors, Audius will collect and

store the contents of chat messages that occur through the chat feature.

● Information you provide to us directly when you contact us. We collect User information when

Users communicate with us through the Service, such as through any “Contact” or “Help”

feature on the Service.

● Surveys. From time to time, we may ask Users to provide us with feedback through surveys or

interviews to help us improve the Service. Such surveys or interviews may be used to collect

information about you. Participation in these surveys and interviews is completely voluntary, and

you therefore have a choice whether or not to disclose your information.

● Information collected automatically. When you use our Service, we or our third-party service

providers may automatically receive and record certain information. For example, this may

2

include your device’s IP address, information about your use of the Service during your current

session and over time (including the pages you view and the files you download), the date and

time of your visit, how you interact with the Service including mouse movements and mouse

clicks, links you click, searches conducted, the website visited before navigating to the Service,

your software and hardware attributes (including browser and operating system type and

version, device type, and device identifiers, such as IDFA or Google Ad ID), and your general

location inferred from IP address. To obtain such information, we or our third-party service

providers may use the following technologies to recognize your device and collect information

about your Service usage:

o Server logs. When you use the Service, we automatically receive and record certain

information from your computer (or other device) and your browser. To obtain such

information, we may use server logs or applications that recognize your device and

gather information about its online activity.

o Cookies. We also use cookies on the Service. Cookies are small files that are stored on

your device by your web browser. A cookie allows us to recognize whether you have

visited before and may store user preferences or other information. We also use cookies

for analytics purposes. If you are concerned about having cookies on your device, you

can set your browser to refuse all cookies or to indicate when a cookie is being set,

allowing you to decide whether to accept it. You can also delete cookies from your

device. However, if you choose to block or delete cookies, certain features of the Service

may not operate correctly.

o Web beacons, tags, pixels, and similar technologies. The emails that you receive from

Audius may use an application known as a “web beacon” (also known as a “tag” or

“pixel”) and similar technologies. Web beacons are small strings of code that provide a

method for delivering a graphic image on a web page or in an email message for the

purpose of transferring data. For example, it may allow an email sender to determine

whether a user has opened a particular email.

o Local storage. We may use Local Storage Objects (LSOs) such as HTML5 to store user

authentication information. Your browser may offer its own management tool to

manage LSOs.

We may combine information collected through the Service with information that we collect in other

contexts, such as information from our email communications or phone calls with you, and data we

collect offline. We will treat such combined information in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

Information on Blockchain Networks

As noted, the Audius streaming service utilizes blockchain networks. This section explains what

information will be on these networks.

When you create an account, your name, user handle, user ID, your location (if you’ve provided one), a

reference to your profile photo (if you’ve provided one), and any Creator tracks are stored on chain along

with the time of creation and/or modification of each of these pieces of information.

3

Your interactions on the Audius streaming service are also stored on chain. These are stored by your

user ID and the time of the action and include: saving or removing a track from your library; creating,

publishing, or deleting playlists; playlist names; playlist content such as tracks and the order of the

tracks; albums; actions to repost tracks, albums, or playlists; following and unfollowing other Users on

Audius. Any comments you make on albums, playlists, or tracks will also be stored on chain and

associated with your name and handle.

Your email address and password are not stored on chain, but your transactions and the above

information are stored both on and off chain by us.

How We Use Information that We Collect

We and the third-party Vendors we work with use the information that we collect for a variety of

purposes related to Audius’ Service and business, including:

● Providing the Service. To create an account for you on Audius, to provide you with the music

uploading, listening, and social experience on our Service, to fulfill the terms of any agreement

you have with us, to respond to your requests, and for other purposes related to managing our

business;

● Communicating with you. To communicate with you regarding your Audius account, updates

regarding our Service, and other administrative issues, and to respond to your questions or

requests;

● Sending emails, newsletters or other promotional messages. To send you newsletters or other

promotional messages regarding our Service or other services that may be of interest to you;

● Conducting analytics and improving our Service. To count and recognize users of the Audius

Service, analyze how the Service is used, improve the Service and the User experience, create

new products and services, conduct analytics, including as described in the section below titled

“Analytics and Interest-based Advertising”;

● Tailoring our content and advertisements. To tailor content on the Audius Service and target

out advertising, including as described in the section below titled “Analytics and Interest-based

Advertising”;

● Compiling aggregated and de-identified information. To compile aggregated and de-identified

statistics or reports that we may share with our partners or other third parties;

● Legal purposes. For legal or other necessary purposes, including as described below in the

section below titled “How We Share information.”

How We Share Information

We share information with third parties for a variety of reasons, including as follows:

● Vendors. We use third-party service providers (Vendors) to help us manage and improve our

Service. These Vendors may collect and use your information only to assist us in achieving the

purposes discussed in this Privacy Policy. For example, we may use third-party Vendors to host

4

our website and perform data storage and processing services, provide help chat service

features, send emails, and perform analytics. Our Vendors are distinct from our Users who act

as Service/Infrastructure Providers as part of the on-chain service.

● Creators. When you transact with a Creator on the Audius Network, we may share your contact

information with that Creator to foster a relationship between the two parties. Note that we

have limited control over how a Creator may use your information.

● Other users of the Service. When you create an account and engage in transactions on the

Service, other Users of the Service may view the on-chain information as described in the

Section “Information on Blockchain Networks” above. Other users may also view the comments

you post and your interactions on the Service. Please ensure you do not submit any information

that will be stored on chain that you do not want to be shared with other users.

● Facebook Custom Audiences and Similar Programs. We may partner with Facebook Twitter and

other social media partners to deliver advertisements to our Users via Facebook Custom

Audiences or similar third-party programs. In order to identify and reach our users on Facebook

or another third-party service, we may share information such as an email address. For more

information about custom audience targeting and how to adjust your social media advertising

preferences, please review the privacy policy of your social media provider.

● Third-party plugins. The Service may integrate third-party plugins (such as a Facebook “like”

button and Twitter “follow” button). Even if you do not click on these plugins, they may collect

information about you, such as your IP address and the pages that you view. They also may set

and/or access cookies or use similar technologies. These plugins are governed by the privacy

policies of the companies providing them.

● Legal purposes. We may use or share your information with third parties when we believe, in

our sole reasonable discretion, that doing so is necessary:

o To comply with applicable law or a court order, subpoena, or other legal process;

o To investigate, prevent, or take action regarding illegal or prohibited activities, suspected

fraud, violations of our rules or terms and conditions, or situations involving threats to

Users, our property, or the property or physical safety of any person or third party;

o To establish, protect, or exercise our legal rights or defend against legal claims.

● Organizational transfers. We may share your information with third parties to facilitate the

financing, securitization, insuring, merger, acquisition, sale, assignment, bankruptcy, or other

disposal of all or part of our organization or assets.

● Aggregated and de-identified information. We may share aggregated and de-identified

information with third parties, such as by publishing or sharing reports with third parties about

trends in the usage of Audius’ streaming service.

Analytics and Interest-based Advertising

5

We partner with certain third-party service providers to collect information to engage in analytics,

auditing, research, and reporting. These third parties may use server logs, web beacons, tags, pixels, and

similar technologies, and they may set and access cookies on your computer or other device.

In particular, we use Google Analytics on our Service to help collect and analyze certain information for

the purposes discussed above. You can learn more about Google Analytics’ data practices by clicking

here and opt out of the use of cookies in web browsers by Google Analytics by clicking here.

We may also use analytics providers, including Mouseflow, FullStory, Hotjar, and Optimizely, that engage

in heat mapping and that record mouse movements, clicks, scrolls, and keystrokes during your use of

Audius. These services help us identify and address technical issues and understand usage of our Service,

which we use to improve the Service for you. You can opt-out of our use of these providers here for

Mouseflow, here for FullStory, here for Optimizely, and here for Hotjar.

We also may partner with third parties to provide advertising services that are targeted based on your

online activities across websites, mobile apps, and devices over time (commonly referred to as

“interest-based advertising”). Our advertising partners may collect information about your activities on

our Services on your current device and combine it with information about your activities on other

websites, mobile apps, and devices. They may collect such information using server logs, cookies, web

beacons, tags, pixels, mobile advertising IDs (such as Apple’s IDFA or Google’s Advertising ID),

cross-device linking, and similar technologies. For example, our advertising partners may use the fact

that you visited our websites or used our mobile apps to target advertising to you on non-Audius

websites and mobile apps on your current device or on other devices you use. You can opt out of

interest-based advertising in web browsers and mobile apps on your current browser or device by

following the instructions below.

For more information about interest-based advertising and cross-device linking, please visit the Network

Advertising Initiative website, the Digital Advertising Alliance website, and the European Interactive

Digital Advertising Alliance website. You may also opt out of interest-based advertising and cross-device

linking in web browsers and mobile apps on your current browser or device by following the instructions

below.

● Web Browser Opt-Out. To opt out in web browsers, please visit http://optout.aboutads.info/,

http://optout.networkadvertising.org, and http://youronlinechoices.eu/. To help preserve the

choices that you make in the DAA’s WebChoices page, you can install the DAA’s “Protect My

Choices” extension that is available at http://www.aboutads.info/PMC. Please note that our

Services do not respond to browser Do Not Track signals at this time.

● Mobile Application Opt-Out. To opt out in mobile apps, you can adjust the advertising

preferences on your mobile device (for example, in iOS, visit Settings \> Privacy \> Advertising \>

Limit Ad Tracking, and in Android, visit Settings \> Google \> Ads \> Opt out of interest-based ads).

You can also opt out for companies that participate in the Digital Advertising Alliance's

AppChoices tool by downloading it at www.aboutads.info/appchoices and following the

instructions in the app. For more information about opting out on mobile devices, please see

https://www.networkadvertising.org/mobile-choice.

Please note that the opt-outs described above will apply only to the specific browser or device from

which you opt out, and therefore you will need to opt out separately on all of your browsers and devices.

If you delete or reset your cookies or mobile advertising identifiers, change browsers (including

6

upgrading certain browsers), or use a different device, any opt-out cookie or tool may no longer work,

and you will need to opt out again. Our Service does not respond to Do Not Track signals at this time.

Third-Party Links, Websites, and Apps

The Service may contain links to websites or services of other third parties. If you follow a link to any of

these websites or services, please note that these websites (and any services that may be accessible

through them) have their own privacy policies. We are not responsible for the privacy practices of other

websites or the information you share through such other websites. We encourage our users to be

aware when they leave the Services and to read the privacy policies applicable to such third-party

websites. This Privacy Policy applies solely to information collected in connection with the Services.

Data Security and Retention

Audius uses physical, technical, and administrative safeguards to protect your information against loss or

unauthorized access, use, modification, or deletion. However, no security program is 100% secure, and

thus we cannot guarantee the absolute security of your information.

Audius retains your information that is not stored on chain for as long as reasonably necessary for its

legitimate business purposes, to provide the Service to you, to fulfill the purposes described in this

Privacy Policy, or as required by law.

Your Rights and Choices

You may review your account information on the Audius streaming service at any time by logging in and

viewing your profile. You may also update certain information directly through your profile. Please

contact us at legal@audius.co with any questions.

You may unsubscribe from promotional communications from us by clicking the “Unsubscribe” link at

the bottom of each message. Please note, you will still receive administrative messages related to your

account from us.

If you would like to opt-out of interest-based advertising, please follow the instructions in the above

section “Analytics and Interest-based Advertising.”

You may have rights under applicable laws to request access to, correction of, deletion of, or restrictions

on the processing of certain information. You may also have rights under applicable laws to opt out of or

withdraw consent to further processing, request copies of your personal data, or lodge a complaint with

a data protection authority in your jurisdiction. To make such request and/or inquire about such rights,

please send us an email at legal@audius.co. For your protection, we may only implement requests

related to information that we have associated with the email address used to send us your request, and

we may need to verify your identity before implementing your request.

As noted, however, on-chain information is immutable and cannot be removed.

Information for Individuals Outside the United States

The information that we collect through or in connection with our Service is controlled by Audius, which

is headquartered in the United States at the address listed in the “Contacting Us” section below. The

7

data that we collect through or in connection with our Service is accessed in the United States for the

purposes described above. Audius also may subcontract the processing of your data to, or otherwise

share your data with, third parties in the United States or other countries outside your country of

residence. The data protection laws in these countries may be different from, and less stringent than,

those in your country of residence. By visiting or using the Service, clicking “I agree” or any other button

indicating your acceptance of this Privacy Policy, or otherwise providing information to Audius, you

expressly consent to such processing.

We will implement data protection mechanisms, as appropriate, to safeguard your information when

accessed or processed outside your country of residence. We may process your data in the United States

as necessary for the performance of our agreements with you or to establish, exercise, or defend legal

claims.

To the extent required by law, our legal basis for processing information will depend on the type of

information at issue and the purpose for which it is collected and used. In some cases, we rely on your

consent to process information, or we process information as necessary for the performance of our

agreements with you. We also may rely on our legitimate interests to process your information, for the

purposes described in this Privacy Policy.

Children’s Privacy

The Service is not intended for individuals deemed to be children under the laws of your jurisdiction. We

request that children do not provide information to us through the Service.

Sensitive Information

We ask that you not send us, and you not disclose, any sensitive information (e.g., social security

numbers, financial information, health information, information related to racial or ethnic origin, political

opinions, religious or philosophical beliefs, trade union membership, genetic or biometric data, or sexual

orientation) on or through the Service or otherwise to us.

Changes to This Privacy Policy

We may revise this Privacy Policy periodically in the future. If we make any material changes, we will

post the revised Privacy Policy on our website with an effective date indicating when the revised Privacy

Policy will take effect. Your continued use of our Service will serve as an acceptance of any changes to

the Policy. We encourage you to review this Privacy Policy periodically.

Contacting Us

If you have any questions or comments regarding our Privacy Policy, please email us at legal@audius.co

or contact us at:

Tiki Labs, Inc.

5940 S Rainbow Blvd.

STE 400 PMB 43362

Las Vegas NV 89118

8
